ILGWU Publications Justice 5780/051 PUBS
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
ILGWU Publications Justice
1931-1995
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union
5780/051 PUBS
6 cubic feet
6 linear ft.
Publications.
Contains issues of Justice published between 1975 and 1995 and 1931-1933.
7128715
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, May 18, 2011
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, April 08, 2019
Biographical / Historical
The International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union was once one of the largest labor unions in the United States founded in 1900 by local union delegates representing about 2,000 members in cities in the northeastern United States. It was one of the first U.S. Unions to have a membership consisting of mostly females, and it played a key role in the labor history of the 1920s and 1930s. The union is generally referred to as the "ILGWU" or the "ILG". The ILGWU grew in geographical scope, membership size, and political influence to become one of the most powerful forces in American organized labor by mid-century. Representing workers in the women's garment industry, the ILGWU worked to improve working and living conditions of its members through collective bargaining agreements, training programs, health care facilities, cooperative housing, educational opportunities, and other efforts. The ILGWU merged with the Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union in 1995 to form the Union of Needle trades, Industrial and Textile Employees (UNITE). UNITE merged with the Hotel Employees and Restaurant Employees Union (HERE) in 2004 to create a new union known as UNITE HERE. The two unions that formed UNITE in 1995 represented only 250,000 workers between them, down from the ILGWU's peak membership of 450,000 in 1969.
Biographical / Historical
Justice was the official organ of the ILGWU from 1919 to 1995. Editions of Justice were published in English, Italian, Spanish, and Yiddish. When compared side by side, the content of some of these different editions of Justice shows significant differences.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of issues of Justice published between 1975-1995. There is also a bound volume from 1931-1933.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5780: ILGWU records 5780/070: ILGWU Publication "The Ladies' Garment Worker" 5780/070 mf: ILGWU Publication "The Ladies' Garment Worker" on Microfilm 5780/051 mf: ILGWU Justice on Microfilm 5780/180: ILGWU Publication "Justice" Index 5780/185 mf: ILGWU Publication "Gerechtigkeit" (Justice) on Microfilm 5780/186: ILGWU Publication "Giustizia" (Justice) 5780/186 mf: ILGWU Publication "Giustizia" (Justice) on Microfilm 5780/201: ILGWU Publication "Justicia" (Justice)
Clothing workers -- Labor unions -- New York (State) -- New York; Clothing workers -- Labor unions -- United States; Textile workers -- New York (State) -- New York; Textile workers -- United States
7128715
- Justice, 1975-1982 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Item 1: Justice, Publication (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Scope and Contents
    By International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union. Item is in English.
- Justice, 1983-1995; Publication (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Item 1: Justice, Publication (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Justice, 1931-1933; Publication (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Justice, 1967; Publication (Box 4, Folder 5)
  July 1, 1967 - December 1, 1967
- Justice, 1967; Publication (Box 4, Folder 4)
  January 1, 1967 - June 15, 1967; Missing May 1, 1967, June 1, 1967
- Justice, 1966; Publication (Box 4, Folder 3)
  January 15, 1966 - December 15, 1966; Missing February 1, 1966, March 1, 1966, March 15, 1966, April 1, 1966, April 15, 1966, May 1, 1966, May 15, 1966, June 1, 1966, June 15,1966, November 15, 1966
- Justice, 1965; Publication (Box 4, Folder 2)
  January 15, 1965 - September 1, 1965; Missing March 1, 1965, April 15,1965, August 15, 1965
- Justice, 1964; Publication (Box 4, Folder 1)
  January 1, 1964 - December 15, 1964; Missing October 15, 1964, November 1, 1964
- Justice, 1969; Publication (Box 5, Folder 4)
  July 1, 1969 - December 1, 1969; Missing July 15, 1969, August 1, 1969
- Justice, 1969; Publication (Box 5, Folder 3)
  January 1, 1969 - June 15, 1969; Missing March 15, 1969
- Justice, 1968; Publication (Box 5, Folder 2)
  July 1, 1968 - December 15, 1968; Missing July 15, 1968, August 15, 1968
- Justice, 1968; Publication (Box 5, Folder 1)
  January 1, 1968 - June 15, 1968
- Justice, 1971; Publication (Box 6, Folder 4)
  July 1, 1971 - December 15, 1971
- Justice, 1971; Publication (Box 6, Folder 3)
  January 1, 1971 - June 15, 1971; Missing January 15, 1971
- Justice, 1970; Publication (Box 6, Folder 2)
  July 15, 1970 - December 15, 1970; Missing September 1, 1970
- Justice, 1970; Publication (Box 6, Folder 1)
  January 1, 1970 - June 15, 1970
- Justice, 1973; Publication (Box 7, Folder 4)
  July 1, 1973 - December 15, 1973
- Justice, 1973; Publication (Box 7, Folder 3)
  January 1, 1973 - June 15, 1973
- Justice, 1972; Publication (Box 7, Folder 2)
  June 15, 1972 - December 15, 1972
- Justice, 1972; Publication (Box 7, Folder 1)
  January 1, 1972 - June 1, 1972
- Justice, 1975; Publication (Box 8, Folder 4)
  July 1, 1975 - December 15, 1975
- Justice, 1975; Publication (Box 8, Folder 3)
  January 1, 1975 - June 15, 1975; Missing May 1, 1975, May 15, 1975
- Justice, 1974; Publication (Box 8, Folder 2)
  July 1, 1974 - December 15, 1974
- Justice, 1974; Publication (Box 8, Folder 1)
  January 1, 1974 - June 15, 1974
- Justice, 1977; Publication (Box 9, Folder 4)
  July 1, 1977 - December 1, 1977
- Justice, 1977; Publication (Box 9, Folder 3)
  January 1, 1977 - May 15, 1977
- Justice, 1976; Publication (Box 9, Folder 2)
  July 1, 1976 - December 15, 1976
- Justice, 1976; Publication (Box 9, Folder 1)
  January 1, 1976 - June 15, 1976; Missing February 1, 1976
- Justice, 1979; Publication (Box 10, Folder 3)
  January 1, 1979 - December 1979; Missing June 1979, August 1979, September 1979
- Justice, 1978; Publication (Box 10, Folder 2)
  July 1, 1978 - December 15, 1978; Missing September 15, 1978
- Justice, 1978; Publication (Box 10, Folder 1)
  January 1, 1978 - June 15, 1978
- Justice, 1984; Publication (Box 11, Folder 5)
  January 1984 - November 1984
- Justice, 1983; Publication (Box 11, Folder 4)
  January 1983 - December 1983
- Justice, 1983; Publication (Box 11, Folder 3)
  February 1983 - December 1983; Missing June 1983
- Justice, 1981; Publication (Box 11, Folder 2)
  January 1981 - November 1981
- Justice, 1980; Publication (Box 11, Folder 1)
  March 1980 - October 1980
- Justice, 1990; Publication (Box 12, Folder 4)
  January 1990 - December 1990; Missing October 1990
- Justice, 1987; Publication (Box 12, Folder 3)
  January 1987 - December 1987
- Justice, 1986; Publication (Box 12, Folder 2)
  January 1986 - December 1986
- Justice, 1985; Publication (Box 12, Folder 1)
  January 1985 - December 1985; Missing September 1985
- Justice, 1995; Publication (Box 13, Folder 5)
  January 1995 - June 1995; Missing February, May 1995
- Justice, 1994; Publication (Box 13, Folder 4)
  January 1994 - December 1994; Missing February 1994, May 1994, August 1994, November 1994
- Justice, 1993; Publication (Box 13, Folder 3)
  January 1993 - December 1993; Missing February 1993, May 1993, August 1993, November 1993
- Justice, 1992; Publication (Box 13, Folder 2)
  January 1992 - December 1992
- Justice, 1991; Publication (Box 13, Folder 1)
  January 1991 - December 1991
- Justice, 1993; Publication (Box 14, Folder 6)
  Hardbound copy: January 1993 - December 1993 (no months February, May, August, or November); copy 2
- Justice, 1993; Publication (Box 14, Folder 5)
  Hardbound copy: January 1993 - December 1993 (no months February, May, August, or November); copy 1
- Justice, 1992; Publication (Box 14, Folder 4)
  Hardbound copy: January 1992 - December 1992
- Justice, 1991; Publication (Box 14, Folder 3)
  Hardbound copy: January 1991 - December 1991
- Justice, 1989; Publication (Box 14, Folder 2)
  Hardbound copy: January 1989 - December 1989
- Justice, 1988; Publication (Box 14, Folder 1)
  Hardbound copy: January 1988 - December 1988
- Justice, 1995; Publication (Box 15, Folder 2)
  Hardbound copy: January 1995 - December 1995 (no months February, May, August, November); each month has a copy in English and a copy in Spanish
- Justice, 1994; Publication (Box 15, Folder 1)
  Hardbound copy: January 1994 - December 1994 (no months February, May, August, or November)